surlybikes.com 2019-05-24

# Surly Bikes Privacy Policy | Surly Bikes

#### **Privacy & Security**

SURLY BIKES is committed to respecting the privacy and security interests of all visitors to our website. SURLY BIKES is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not disclose, sell, share or rent this information to any other individual or entity except as disclosed in this statement.

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. This site legitimately runs under the auspices of SURLY BIKES. All information sent to this site in an SSL session (https) is 128 bit encrypted, protecting against disclosure to third parties. All information sent to this site in a standard session (http) is not encrypted, potentially disclosing it to third parties.

**Collection and Use of Personal, Non-Personal Data**

SURLY BIKES reserves the right to log and analyze information gathered from a user’s visit to the SURLY BIKES website. This information includes personal (name, email address) and non-personal (browsing patterns, number of site logins) data.

Personal Data Collection and Use

Personal data is collected when users provide information to SURLY BIKES. As an example, a user may request to be added to SURLY BIKES’ email communications, provide a product review or product question. Additionally, when a user completes a new account application with SURLY BIKES, personal data, including, but not limited to, name, email address, and phone number are captured. SURLY BIKES uses this information in a number of ways as part of normal business communications. Personal data may also be used to communicate marketing or promotional information that we feel may be of interest to you. As a user, you have the option to unsubscribe from marketing or promotional email communications at any time.

**_PowerReviews_**

We use the service [PowerReviews](https://www.powerreviews.com/privacy-policy/) to collect and process personal data — ratings and reviews, photos and videos, questions and answers. By submitting star rating, review, comment, photo, video and other user-generated content you give your consent to display your comment, photo, video and other user-generated content on our website. For further details, please see PowerReviews privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.powerreviews.com/privacy-policy/).

**_Location Information_**

When you click the “Buy Now” button our site will determine your location from your IP address and recommend retailers who are closest to your location.  By clicking “Buy Now” you give your consent to our detection and processing of your IP address to provide the requested local retailer information.

Non-Personal Data Collection and Use

Non-personal data collected include your web usage patterns when you interact with SURLY BIKES’ website. We use tracking technologies to capture data that is intended to better understand how users interact with our website, measure the success of marketing campaigns, and to ensure that the user experience is optimized.

**_Tracking Technologies_**

SURLY BIKES’ website uses technologies like cookies, tags, scripts and logs to capture details specific to your browsing patterns when you visit our website pages. We use analytics packages like Google Analytics and Hotjar to make sense of this data and understand how users interact with our site. None of the information collected is personally identifiable. Users who wish to opt out of Google Analytics can learn how to do so by visiting the following [site](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Users who wish to opt out of Hotjar may do so [here](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

**Google Analytics**

Our website uses Google Analytics to collect information about the use of our website. Google Analytics collects information from users such as age, gender, interests, demographics, how often they visit our website, what pages they visit, and what other websites they have used before coming to our website. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to analyze traffic and to improve our website. We have enabled Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit our website, not your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected using Google Analytics with Personal Data. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. For more information on how Google collects and processes your data, visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.  You can prevent Google Analytics from using your information by opting out at this link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**HOTJAR**

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize our service and your user experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our user’s experiences (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our user’s behavior and their devices (in particular device IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile by Hotjar, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

**Disclosure of User Data to Third Parties**

SURLY BIKES currently shares the following information with suppliers: account name, mailing address, and phone number. SURLY BIKES does not share email addresses with suppliers or other third parties. SURLY BIKES does not share non-personal data, as described above, with third parties.

**Third-Party Links**

This website contains links to other related industry sites. Please be aware that SURLY BIKES is not responsible for the content, security or privacy practices of any other sites. These linked sites are only for your convenience and therefore you access them at your own risk.
